# CESAR CORDERO JR

2330 N 36th Ave., Phoenix, AZ 85009 - 786-203-8603 - cesarjr305@gmail.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

The utmost goal is to obtain a position within a company that is seeking an individual who can exceed expectations of daily tasks, resolve technical issues with efficiency, approach innovation with excitement and ease towards the future. An individual who excels in building rapport with customers using technical, analytical and empathy skills to obtain an extraordinary customer experience.

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Over 10 years as an IT Technician with a incredible experience in facing day to day technical issues with efficiency and amazing Customer Service attitude. Committed to human development and company growth. Positive and determined problem solver with incredible analytical, understanding, and creative skills. Seeking IT position that can challenge me and provide company growth whilst using my skills to resolve issues and work effectively.

#### **SKILLS**

- Proficient in English and Spanish to provide and receive clear and effective instructions.
- Conducted research in technical fields to provide support to Latin American countries. Including but not limited to South America, ALAC, Islands, etc.
- Capable of monitoring and managing small and large business systems per daily demands needed.
- Knowledgeable in coordinating and executing installations of technical equipment per business needs, including but not limited to troubleshooting.
- Coordinated trainings with upcoming ideas and innovations, including new material to raw audiences, such as other teams, managers, and leaders, in public meetings for products and systems that were "yet to be released" while maintaining discrepancy.
- Ongoing side work as a self contractor for Low Voltage performing but not limited to, structured cabling, reading blueprints, coordinating projects from initial to conclusion, installing network systems, access points, rack building and cable dressing.
- Managed internally for business as well as being responsible for providing technical support beyond company ability for international clients to maintain professional relationship and show exceptional service.
- Drawn up plans of actions for correct procedures to be followed before initiating action to maintain efficiency and professionally for small and large businesses.
- Handled Active Directory to track and assist smooth transitions per business needs.
- Expert in building rapport with clients in difficult and easy scenarios.
- Knowledgeable in handling small to corporate business network configurations.
- Experience in splicing and terminating and configuring Cat5/ Cat6 and trained for Fiber Optic termination using IPv4 and IPv6.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FITNESS CONSULTANT/FACILITY MANAGER, EOS FITNESS; PHOENIX, AZ - 2019-PRESENT

- Build rapport with prospects and existing members for the facility
- Engage with members to ensure their success
- Maintain a professional environment with members and employees when dealing with financial responsibilities
- Note and track sales numbers daily per business demands with KPI's
- Explain and understand the process for new and returning members for new memberships
- Manage and execute club cleanliness
- Build janitorial and equipment maintenance and safety
- Enforce gym rules
- Ensure proper operation of all club areas
- Hire, train, supervise, coach and evaluate maintenance staff

## SALES REPRESENTATIVE, BEST BUY; FLORIDA CITY, FL - 2017-2019

- Exclusive to Computer/Apple department
- Actively engage customers to increase sales in entire store
- Simplify complex technical solutions and/or plans for customers
- Demonstrated active listening and response to attend customer to provide excellent customer and suggest products that would fit customers needs
- Subject matter expert in Computers and Apple department to provide information
- Working as a team with the rest of the store to direct customers to other experts per customers demands
- Fulfill daily check ins to obtain sale quotas and asses a procedure of follow through
- Maintained certification through training to appropriately sell the correct products and services to clients
- Cleanliness of store and department during downtime hours (downstock, laser line, sweep, dust. etc)

## SPANISH AT HOME SUPERVISOR, APPLE INC.; HOMESTEAD, FL - 2014-2017

- Assisted peers worldwide with AppleCare questions
- Processed contract maintenance requests using various internal tools.
- Documented/Logged issue statements and resolutions on a case by case basis
- Monitor wordlists daily
- Managed and reported schedule and tasks per job requirement
- Supported Wireless Multimedia, iOS, Mac, OS X, iTunes, iPhones, iPads, iPods, Apple TV
- Responsible for attending new emails on a daily basis
- Escalated tickets to specific departments such as SSE, Admins, Agreement Admin, Customer Relations on a case by case basis
- Followed and assisted others with internal procedures within company policies
- Managed my calls and appointments depending on customer and business needs
- Stayed up to date to all the new changes to happening within the company

## INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, KING OCEAN; DORAL, FL - 2005-2014

- Assisted users with system, software functionality and technical issues
- Provided training to employees in computer application and usage
- Participated in system changes and updates in company functions to the up to date software.
- Configure and test new units with system functions that would be adequate for business
- Evaluated software vendors and solutions for best use for company purposes
- Installed, configured, managed and troubleshot technical equipment
- Responsible for company's main mobile wireless account and hardware
- Upgraded, installed, managed and troubleshot TCP/IP IPv4 and IPv6 networks on different computer platforms including DNS and DHCP Servers
- Documented and logged network issues and solutions
- Installed and managed network security systems (Cisco/Barracuda/etc.)
- Set, spliced and terminated Cat5e cables for network and data usage for office/business use.
- Translated and trained staff in a bilingual environment for best comprehension for services using iOS, Android, BIOS, and HTML platforms
- Responsible for installing and managing low voltage telephone lines (66 Block / 110 Block)

- Installed and programmed DVR for CCTV Cameras after analog CCTV installations
- Handled Active Directory systems using Citrix, or Outlook Enterprise, or company provided programs to make smooth transitions when changes needed
- Trained for modular fiber optic splicing and termination

## **EDUCATION**

MIAMI DADE COLLEGE — ASSOCIATES AA, 2011-2012 LOUDON HIGH SCHOOL — GENERAL STUDIES HS, 2000-2004

References available upon request.